Finding Aid for the Mark Sandrich scripts PASC.0262
UCLA Library Special Collections
Mark Sandrich scripts
1935-1938
UCLA Library Special Collections
Sandrich, Markin, 1900-1945
PASC.0262
0.4 linear feet (1 box)
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source and date of receipt unknown.
Biographical / Historical
Mark Sandrich was born August 26, 1900 in New York City; he studied at Columbia University, and in 1923 went to Holywood to start his career in films; he began directing comedy shorts (1927) and made his debut as a feature film director the following year; he is best known for his Fred Astaire-Ginger Rodgers musical films; Sandrich died March 4, 1945.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9948577473606533
We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special Collections.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of scripts related to the career of Mark Sandrich. Includes various script drafts for Carefree and Top Hat.
- CAREFREE (RKO, 1938)
  - Screenplay by Hagar Wilde and Dudley Nichols, 1938 February 25 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Screenplay by Hagar Wilde and Dudley Nichols, 1938 March 4 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Revised screenplay by Allan Scott and Ernest Pagano, 1938 May 4 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Revised screenplay by Allan Scott and Ernest Pagano, 1938 May 7 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Revised screenplay by Allan Scott and Ernest Pagano, 1938 May 7 with changes of May 9 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Revised screenplay by Allan Scott and Ernest Pagano, 1938 May 7 with changes through May 10. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes memo from Joseph Breen, 1938 May 17.
  - Script pages, 1938 May 19 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Script pages, 1938 May 23 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Script pages, 1938 June 10 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Script pages, 1938 June 14 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Review of Sets and Revised Dream Sequence, 1938 July 1 - 1938 July 2 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- TOP HAT (RKO, 1935)
  - Rough Synopsis, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - First rough draft screenplay by Dwight Taylor and Allan Scott, 1935 March 11 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Screenplay by Allan Scott and Dwight Taylor, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Estimating script by Dwight Taylor and Allan Scott with lyrics and music by Irving Berlin, 1935 March 15 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    General
    Lightly annotated.
- RKO Story Department
  - Readers' reports, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Includes reports on stories by: Elaine Sterne Carrington; Maxine McBride; Robert Milton and Rex Smith; Octavus Roy Cohen.